Steve Thompson

Brookings, SD 57006 | Email: sthmpsn@gmail.com | Phone: 631-834-8881 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/steven-thompson-10a5071b | GitHub: github.com/sthmpsn | Portfolio: sthmpsn.github.io

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer and experienced IT leader specializing in the deployment and support of Engineering Lifecycle Management tools. Known for creative problem solving, ability to rapidly learn new applications and technologies, with strong leadership skills. Have been described as "the glue that holds the department together" and recipient of multiple "Pioneer", "Pathfinder", "Count on Me", and "One Team" awards demonstrating the ability to innovate, collaborate, and provide stellar service to internal and external clients.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PowerShell, Perl, SQL

Frameworks & Technologies: Mongoose, Sequelize, Node, Express, React, Handlebars, Bootstrap

Databases: Mongo, MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Firebase

OS & Applications: Windows Server, RedHat Linux, Heroku, Atlassian Jira, Bitbucket, Crowd, and Confluence

Data Center, IBM ClearCase and ClearQuest, Coverity, Collaborator, Git, MS Project, MS Visio

Methods: Configuration Management, Application Management Lifecycle, SDLC, Continuous Improvement

PROJECTS

React Clicky Game | Demo: sthmpsn.github.io/clicky-game | | Code: github.com/sthmpsn/clicky-game

- Summary: Front-End React game with Simpsons theme that tests your memory
- Role: Developer
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node, React

TryAthlete | Demo: my-try-athlete.herokuapp.com || Code: github.com/sthmpsn/TryAthlete

- Summary: React app that helps people track their personal tri-athlete and fitness goals in a fun way
- Role: Project Manager, DB Architect, Full Stack Developer
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, React-Bootstrap, MERN Stack, Semantic-UI-React, React-Youtube

Google Book Search | Demo: my-google-booksearch.herokuapp.com|| Code: http://bit.ly/2KABAg9

- Summary: Front-End React app that helps search for google books and save info to a Mongo database
- Role: Developer
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node, Express, React, Mongoose, Axios

CYOA | Demo: cyoa-bc.herokuapp.com/ || Code: github.com/sthmpsn/cyoa

- **Summary**: The application is a create-your-own-adventure-style game boot camp theme.
- Role: Full Stack Developer
- **Technologies**: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express, js, Express-validate, Sequelize.js, bcryptjs, MySQL, Heroku, JawsDB, Gauge.js

EXPERIENCE

Principal IT Analyst | BAE Systems, Inc. | Remote

2016 - 2020

- Architect and deploy a set of modern Engineering Development Lifecycle tools consisting of Atlassian Crowd, Jira, Bitbucket, and Confluence resulting in a license cost savings of approximately \$3M
- Manage a cross-sector team consisting of three different sectors and 5 different business areas which
 resulted in a reduction of ticket redirects, deployment and upgraded turnaround time and increased
 awareness of security vulnerabilities
- Team Lead and Subject Matter Expert for 7 applications consisting of 6 team members and supporting over 3000+ users

Senior IT Analyst | BAE Systems, Inc. | Austin, TX

2012 - 2016

- Lead IT initiatives such as server and license consolidation effort leading to \$420K in annual savings.
- Responsible for rolling out of the Coverity Static Analysis tool which immediately saved a pilot program over \$300K in defect detection hours and an increased external customer satisfaction
- Gathered requirements, planned, tested, executed, and maintained numerous engineering tool suites designed to support the rapid release of high quality products

IT Analyst II | BAE Systems, Inc. | Greenlawn, NY

2009 - 2012

- Provided ClearCase and ClearQuest support for the Engineering Function consisting of 2000+ users located at geographically dispersed sites
- Planned closed area deployments of Engineering Tools at offsite locations and provide tool training to ensure tool adoption success

Computer Systems Analyst II | BAE Systems, Inc. | Greenlawn, NY

2004 - 2008

- Managed 20+ programs in the Software Engineering department as Software Configuration Manager (SCM) with approximately 130 Software Engineers onsite and 20 at remote sites
- Created Software Development and Configuration Plans for projects exceeding \$400K in sales
- Lead site-wide license renewal project which resulted in over \$60K savings per year
- Ensured software processes comply with CMMI level 5 certification and participate in DOD audits
- Developed branching strategies and establish software baselines to ensure integrity

IT Network Engineer | Langistic Networks | Hauppauge, NY

2003 - 2004

- Reduced Helpdesk backlog resulting in a 93% increase in response time for the East Islip School District
- Build, configured and integrated workstations into customer existing infrastructures
- Terminated, ran, and tested cables to ensure network connectivity from workstation to server

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN

Master of Business Administration, Information Systems Management: Dowling College, Oakdale, NY

Bachelor of Arts, Business Administrator of Information Technology: Briarcliffe College, Patchogue, NY

CERTIFICATIONS

CompTIA Network+ –ID#: COMP001020665277

CompTIA Security+ - ID#: COMP001020665277

ITIL v3 Foundations - ID#: 979888